<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A true and faithful account of the seizing thirty seven suspected persons, and among them some known papists, who were caballing against the government in a tavern, with the manner of their apprehension.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B06217</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T2469</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226015</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52612463</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52612463</idno>
            <idno type="VID">179687</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B06217)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 179687)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2796:25)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A true and faithful account of the seizing thirty seven suspected persons, and among them some known papists, who were caballing against the government in a tavern, with the manner of their apprehension.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Reprinted in the year, 1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>At head of text: "Licens'd Septemb. 6. 1689."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Sedition --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-03</date>
            <label>Elspeth Healey</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Rekeyed and resubmitted</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div n="true and faithful" type="account">
            <pb facs="tcp:179687:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->
            <head>A True and Faithful Account of the ſeizing Thirty ſeven ſuſpected Perſons, and amongſt them ſome known Papiſts, who were Caballing againſt the Government in a Tavern, with the manner of their Apprehenſion.</head>
            <p>Licens'd <hi>Septemb.</hi> 6. 1689.</p>
            <p>THe laſt Week ſome Deſigning Perſons, as mentioned in the <hi>Gazette,</hi> took the boldneſs to Seize both the <hi>Scots</hi> and <hi>Iriſh</hi> Mails, carrying away the King's Pacquets from each; which as it is a matter of that high Concern, ſo it Demonſtrably beſpeaks, that the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Party, who have a natural Propenſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to practiſe Miſchief againſt the Government, deſign to have ſome extraor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary Project put in Execution: But, as praiſed be God, none of their Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trivances have hitherto met with Succeſs, ſo the merit of the Cauſe, as well as the indefatigable care of the Government is ſuch, as to defeat the Deſigns of the Diſaffected and <hi>Grumbletonian</hi> Incendiaries, a more notable Inſtance has not been extant.</p>
            <p>The Mails aforeſaid being ſeized, and therby the King's Advice diſcover'd, extraordinary Diligence was uſed, to find out the Authors of this miſchievous Proceeding; and conſidering that not the Gaols, but rather ſome Taverns ought to be inſpected, a double Diligence and Scrutiny was made into ſeveral places, where, under the Notion of meeting and drinking purely with a Friend there, Complotting and Caballing was the Intent, and as the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quel demonſtrates, the Cauſe. So the Government having got Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, that a more than ordinary Number of Gentlement, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> held a Ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dezvous at one <hi>Brooks</hi>'s, who keeps the <hi>New Cock</hi> and <hi>Bottle</hi> in the <hi>Strand</hi> near <hi>Charing-croſs.</hi> Two Meſſengers were appointed on <hi>Thurſday</hi> Evening to beat up their Quarters, who, conſidering the Number of the Enemy they were like to Encounter with, prudently repaired to the Captain of the Guard at <hi>Whitehall,</hi> and he forthwith ſent a Lieutenant with one File of Granadiers, and four of Musquets, to aſſiſt them in the Action; Command being firſt gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to load with Ball, and not to ſpeak a word one to another in their paſſage; which was performed with that Precaution and Diligence, that they arrived at the aforeſaid Tavern without the leaſt Miſtruſt or Preknowledge, who bold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly entering the Houſe, without ſtaying for the Drawer to ſhew them a Room, they found out one themſelves, but the Door being ſhut, took the liberty to force an Entrance, where meeting with a great Number of <hi>Papists,</hi> they, like the true <hi>Iriſh,</hi> were ſo baſhful at their ſight, that ſome hid themſelves in the Chimney, behind the Curtains, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and would have diſpoſed of their Papers, but were forced to ſurrender themſelves with their Weapons, and what they had about them that might be miſchievous. The like diligence was uſed in o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther parts of the Houſe, where was ſcarce a place but they found ſome, and others eſcaping on the Tops of the Houſes; but being brought all into a Room, and commanded to ſit down, there was found to be Thirty ſeven of them, beſides a Woman, there being little Miſchief done where one of their Sex is not concerned.</p>
            <p>The Lieutenant, and Meſſengers took the Names of them <hi>Seriatim,</hi> and found divers <hi>Papiſts,</hi> ſeveral Officers and other Soldiers, ſome whereof had formerly rid in the Lord <hi>Dover</hi>'s Troop of Guards, under the Late King <hi>James:</hi> And ſome of the <hi>Grumbletonian</hi> Gang, who finding the Late King's Intereſt in all the Three Kingdoms to be near Expiring, would like a Candle give the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er Blaſt at going out. And there was ſuch Cauſe found againſt the Maſter of the Houſe, tho he pleaded he never ſaw them before, as to keep him a Priſoner with them. For moſt part of the Night they continued in the Tavern, but afterwards 21 of them were ſent to a Meſſengers in <hi>St. Martin's-lane,</hi> and 16 to anothers, where they are kept Priſoners, while their Papers can be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uſed, and they Examined.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Re-printed in the Year, 1689.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
